LUIS VILLARREAL

Software Engineer

in/luis-villarreal7 | github.com/luisv7 | luisvillarreal.netlify.app

I'm a tech enthusiast who loves learning new technologies and helping others. Experience building eCommerce websites. Business and analytical mindset with a focus on excellence in customer experience. I like to enhance my skills in computer science, IOS Development, and graphic design.

Skills

Languages / Engine: HTML, CSS, Javascript, EJS, Python, SQL, Swift

Databases: MongoDB

Libraries/Frameworks/Env.: React, Node.js, Express.js, AJAX, Mongoose, Django, Bootstrap, Bulma, MUI

Platforms Used: Shopify, WordPress, Magento, Shift4Shop, 3dcart, Lightspeed, WIX, Square-space

Design: Photoshop, Illustrator, Infinity Photo, Infinity Designer,

Other: JSON, Rest, API's, OOP, SEO

Work Experience

Software Engineer

General Assembly April 2022 - Present

Project 1 - Lyrics Finder | HTML, CSS, JS, Bulma, API

This browser application will display artist information along with the most popular songs, YouTube video, and lyrics. Simply search for an artist/singer's name. Listen, watch and sing along!

- Created an app using 3 different API's in order to display all results.
- Created an application with a mobile-first approach and styled the application using Bulma (flexbox layouts).

GitHub: https://github.com/luisv7/project1

Project 2 - Table Reservation | Javascript, CSS, Node.js, EJS, Express, MongoDB/Mongoose

This browser application will help restaurant owners manage their guests/bookings. Great features such as searching by name, date, and time. Additionally, it will keep a guest book/record of all guests that have previously booked.

- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Used EJS Templating.
- Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB backend handle all (CRUD) create, read, update, and delete
 operations. Tested all backend routes during development using Postman.

GitHub: https://github.com/luisv7/TableRes-Manager

Project 3 - Ecom Dash | React.js, Node.js, Express, MongoDB/Mongoose, Javascript, CSS, Material UI

A browser application where you can create your own eCommerce store. Just simply create/add your own products and have a modern layout of all your products. Stay tuned for new features.

- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Used React to handle the frontend.
- Used Firebase for user login and manage each user's stores.

GitHub: https://github.com/luisv7/ecom-dash-frontend GitHub: https://github.com/luisv7/ecom-dash-frontend

Software Engineer / Founder

LA Express Distribution LLC

Aug 2020 - Present La Puente, CA

- Building a strategy, planning, developing, and executing business plans.

- Monitoring performance analytics, website traffic, and product performance; and duties such as networking for the company, developing business strategies, creating marketing plans, setting up processes and systems, and growing a sustainable organization.
- Developed financial plans to determine break-even points. Ensure long-term solvency, and set budgets as the company grows.
- Create, plan, design, and maintain an e-commerce website.

Website: laexpressdistribution.com

Director of E-commerce / Manager

Diego Wireless Inc.

July 2016 - May 2020 Los Angeles, CA

- Implemented a brand new POS system. (Lightspeed Omni Channel)
- Designed a brand B2B e-commerce website. (Over 15K SKU's)
- Oversee the day-to-day e-commerce operations, maintenance, and user experience. Including site navigation, content development, and promotional campaigns.
- Project Manager and brand creator/designer of Mila Products & Accessories. Including product sourcing, packaging, and design.
- Managing the company's Amazon, and eBay store.
- Creating and developing digital marketing content such as web banners, email ads, flyers, etc.
- Creating and tracking weekly email marketing campaigns.

Website: diegowireless.com

E-commerce Specialist

UPC Medical Supplies Jan. 2016 - June 2016

South El Monte, CA

- Managing the company's Amazon, and eBay store.
- Designing the website architecture for a brand new e-commerce website. (Shopify)
- Creating and developing digital marketing content such as web banners, email ads, flyers, etc.
- Google Analytics
- Email Marketing. (Mailchimp)

Website: www.acuwarehouse.com

Education

General Assembly - Software Engineer

April 2022 - Oct. 2022

Citrus College - Computer Science, Associate of Science (AS)

2011 - 2016

Languages

English | Spanish